Glaucia Lemos - Developer Advocate (Software Engineer) @ Microsoft

■ glaucia_lemos86@hotmail.com | in https://www.linkedin.com/in/glaucialemos/ https://github.com/glaucia86



SUMMARY

Software Engineer with more than +10 years development experience in JavaScript, TypeScript & Node.js (BackEnd) and also in .NET C# with national & international experience from small to large companies. Working with different technologies, frameworks and programming languages, such as JavaScript (Server-side: Node.Js), TypeScript, .NET C# and also other Cloud Technologies (Microsoft Azure). Ability to quickly grasp any new Technologies and concepts. Glaucia love's to share your knowledge and support collaborative work. She is also strong in communication with different cultures and peoples. Native in Portuguese. Domain in Spanish and English (Advanced level) and also in Mandarin Chinese (basic level).

EDUCATION

Associate Degree in Systems Analysis and Development – Faculdades Integradas de Jacarepaguá – Rio de Janeiro, RJ, Feb. 2011 - Dec 2013. (GAP: 8.5/10.0)

Technical High School, specialization in Desktop Applications: Colégio Estadual Brigadeiro Schorcht - Rio de Janeiro, RJ, Feb. 2001 - Dec 2004

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Microsoft - Developer Advocate II JavaScript/Node.js & TypeScript | Dec 2019 - actual

Belonging to the JavaScript/Node.js in Azure Cloud Advocacy Team with focus primarily on the overall experience of JavaScript developers in Azure.

Mission

To improve the quality of our JavaScript service offerings in Microsoft's Cloud offerings through direct product feedback, Community engagement, and content that is intentionally aligned with our cloud growth strategy.

Responsibilities

Create and share diverse content and demonstrations spanning beginner to advanced levels for developing, deploying, managing, and scaling Azure applications. Promote Azure products and services actively in local communities through various channels. Establish connections with prominent local developer leaders, gaining their trust in Microsoft technologies. Cultivate relationships with influencers, nurture a thriving technical community, and prioritize and communicate product feedback and technical issues with engineering. Contribute to open-source projects and create impactful applications to engage and win over developers. Utilize data, experiments, and customer feedback to foster community growth and relay valuable insights to the Product Team.

Microsoft - Regional Cloud Advocate in Latin America | Mar 2019 - Dec 2019

Mission:

The mission of the Cloud Advocacy team is to win the hearts and minds of Developers through authenticity, community, and technical engagement. The Cloud Advocacy team is first and foremost pivoted on enabling a healthy ecosystem for technical communities to create and build things in the cloud.

Responsibilities:

Create and share diverse content and demonstrations spanning beginner to advanced levels for developing, deploying, managing, and scaling Azure applications. Promote Azure products and services actively in local communities through various channels. Establish connections with prominent local developer leaders, gaining their trust in Microsoft technologies. Cultivate relationships with influencers, nurture a thriving technical community, and prioritize and communicate product feedback and technical issues with engineering. Contribute to open-source projects and create impactful applications to engage and win over developers. Utilize data, experiments, and customer feedback to foster community growth and relay valuable insights to the Product Team.

HACKDEV - Software Developer (Self Employee) | Apr 2016 - March 2019 (3y)

Consulting, Training, and Project Development in different programming languages, such as MEAN (MongoDb, Express.Js, Angular.Js, and Node.js), ASP.NET & ASP.NET CORE, C#, among other programming languages. Providing, therefore, consultancy and web development applications, new solutions, and the use of good practices in development. Projects that I worked:

Raro Interatividade: 04/2016 – 11/2017;
2PC Software: 11/2017 - 12/2017 (Axa);

Udemy: 11/2017 – Actual;
 Livima: 01/2017 - 03/2017;
 Seven: 10/2017 - 04/2018 (Viceri)

• ESX: 05/2018 - 08/2018

Projects Environments: Front-End, Multi-Cloud, and Back-End.

ZOOX SMART DATA - Software Developer | Sept 2018 - December 2018 (4m)

Development of different and especially innovative Hotel products with the Zoox Labs Team. Including an innovative application called: Zoox Smart Pass. Which is a convenient check-in using face recognition. Project Environment: Node.js (Koa.js Framework), Angular 6, Typescript, Vue.js, REST APIs, Test-Driven Development (TDD), Cloud Platforms (AWS), Artificial Intelligence using Face Recognition, Microservice Architecture, Version Control, and Agile / Scrum Methodology & Jira.

RESOURCE IT SOLUTIONS - Software Engineer | Apr 2017 - Sept 2017 (6m)

Maintenance and development of new Web Applications using ASP.NET MVC and .NET 4.5 to the JBS USA client remotely. Propose new solutions and technologies for the improvement of applications. Propose improvements in the code aiming at better performance for the project. Design and create application databases in SQL Management Studio. Implement business logic in .NET. Projects Environments: Front-End, Multi-Cloud, and Back-End.

GLOBAL LOGIC LATAM - Software Developer | May 2015 - Dec 2015 (8m)

Project for a customer in Brazil but developed in Buenos Aires, Argentina. Developing and maintaining WEB Application for one of the largest insurance companies in the world. Projects Environments: Front-End, Multi-Cloud, and Back-End.

TOP DOWN SISTEMAS - Software Developer | Dec 2013 - Dec 2014 (1y)

Development, customizations, tests, and maintenance on SisAMIL (Sistema Integrado de Saúde Amil) from TopSaude Application using Oracle 11g database along with PL/SQL programming and Asp Classic and C# Asp.NET. Front-End: JavaScript, HTML, CSS and jQuery. Problem test and fixes analysis through QA Hewlett-Packard software related to the company's system. Projects Environments: Front-End, Multi-Cloud, and Back-End.